Muhammad Hazim Bin Sulaiman

Telephone: +6597221283 Email: e0031232@u.nus.edu URL: hajimss.github.io

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/muhammad-hazim-bin-sulaiman-3386191a0



Executive Summary

Accomplished Mechanical Engineering graduate, multifaceted in engineering and computing skills. Possesses vast experience in design engineering. Keen to take on a diverse range of challenges, individually or as a team. Has strong interest in FinTech and currently developing skills relating to it.

Work Experience

Jul 2018 - Dec 2018

Mechanical Engineer (Intern), Schlumberger (Singapore Well Testing Centre - SWTC)

- Supported SWTC's new product development department in prototyping a new version of their multiphase flowmeter
- Created CAD (Computer-Aided Design) models, assemblies and drawings and assisted in physical assembles
- Extended support to other departments where help in calculation or modelling is needed
- Studied applications of Finite Element Analysis
- Obtained a clearer picture of oil and gas industry, including offshore technologies

May 2014 – Jun 2016

Firefighter (NS), Singapore Civil Defence Force

- Performed firefighting and rescue operations as a firefighter
- Responsible for logistics and equipment maintenance of firefighting equipment within station

Education

July 2020 - Present

Introduction to Fintech, Hong Kong University on edX (HKUx)

• Online course that provides introductory knowledge on FinTech

Aug 2016 - May 2020

Bachelor of Engineering (Mechanical Engineering), National University of Singapore

- Specialised in Offshore Oil & Gas Technology
- GPA: 3.83 (after Year 4 Sem 2)
- Relevant coursework: Fluid Mechanics, Strength of Materials, Manufacturing Processes, Engineering Innovation and Modelling, Engineering Thermodynamics
- Technical electives: Offshore Oil and Gas Technology Specialisation Study, Robot Mechanics, Corrosion of Materials & Vibration Theory and Applications

Jul 2018 - Aug 2018

Summer Exchange, Hanyang University (Korea)

Modules: Heat Transfer & Calculus

Jan 2012 - Dec 2013

A Levels, Meridian Junior College

Past Projects

Design Project (Autonomous Grass Cutter)

- Led a team of six to create an autonomous grass-cutting robot
- Collaborated with Catalyst Connector Pte Ltd and fulfilled their project objectives

- Allocated specific tasks to each member and monitored project's timeline by utilising project management tools
- In charge of robot's shell modelling and manufacturing, using Solidworks and machineries; structural analysis was also carried out with Ansys

Final Year Project (Supersonic Gas Ejector Design and Performance Evaluation)

- An individual project where pressure values of a supersonic gas ejector were investigated, and data and graphs were obtained to chart performances of gas ejectors
- Achieved a deeper understanding of thermodynamics and fluid mechanics

Skills

- Proficient in CAD applications such as Solidworks, Solid Edge and Creo
- Experienced in FEA (structural analysis and computational fluid dynamics)
- Language: English (Native), Malay (Native), Spanish (Elementary)
- Learnt C and C++ programming as an unrestricted module
- Web development skills: javascript language, version control system (git)
- Database management: MySQL

Co-Curricular Participation

Mechanical Engineering Camp Committee

 Safety officer; supervised and kept a lookout for potential risks and its probability involved during camp activities and ensured hazards are kept at a minimum

NUS Open house

• Welfare; in charge of distributions of welfare gifts to open house guests

Temasek Hall (2016 - 2020)

- Main Committee of Sports Management Board;
- Participated in Floorball, Soccer and Touch Rugby for Inter-Hall Games 2017, 2018, 2019 & 2020
- Member of Vox (Chorale and Acapella group)

Temasek Hall (2020 - present)

• Class Ambassador; initiates gathering of alumnus for upcoming hall events